Patrick Alvarez

(305) 965 - 4181 | patrick.g.alvarez@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-g-alvarez/ https://github.com/patrickga94 https://patrick-alvarez.herokuapp.com/

Summary

After five years in the fine dining world, driven by my passion for problem solving and the desire to create something meaningful, I made the switch to software engineering. My background in theatre and hospitality gives me a unique advantage in forging connections with new people and delivering unparalleled customer service, and during my time at General Assembly I grew proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python, with a focus on the MERN tech stack.

Skills

- Languages & Frameworks: JavaScript, Node, Express, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Mongoose, React, Python, Django
- Management & Deployment: Git, GitHub, Command Line
- Databases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Methodologies: Object Oriented Programming, MVC Pattern, Test-Driven Development, Responsive Design, Authentication, User Stories, ERDs, Wireframing

Experience

General Assembly

Feb 2022 - May 2022

Software Engineering Immersive Fellow

Remote

- 12-week, 400+ hour training program focused in Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, MongoDB, SQL, Python, etc.
- Homie Quest:
 - Created a side-scrolling video game using HTML (specifically the Canvas element), CSS, and JavaScript in which a player avoids obstacles and collects power ups to reach their friend's house.
- The Adventurer's Spellbook:
 - Built a full-stack application using Node.js, JavaScript, Mongoose, Express, Liquid, CSS, and Bootstrap that serves as a companion to Dungeons and Dragons 5th edition. The app allows users to create, view, update, and delete characters, add a list of spells pulled from a third-party API to the characters, and create their own custom spells.
- AdventureR:
 - Lead a team to build a full-stack application with its own API utilizing Mongoose, Node.js,
 Express, JavaScript, React, mapbox, CSS, and Bootstrap. The idea behind the app was to
 connect fitness fans and promote wellbeing. As such, it allows users to log outdoor recreational
 activities called "adventures", view other user's adventures including a map of the adventure
 area and the current weather and temperature, as well as comment on other user's adventures.
- Happy houR:
 - Built a full-stack application with its own API utilizing Mongoose, Express, React, Node.js, CSS, Bootstrap, the Google Maps API, Google Places API, and the Google Geocoder API. The app allows bars and restaurants to log happy hours with information about deals, location, and hours. Establishments can also add tags to their happy hours for searching purposes. Guests

can then view indexes of happy hours based on their location, search for happy hours by location or by tag, view their information along with a map to the location and user reviews, and add/remove happy hours to a favorites list that they can then access.

Kumiko May 2020 - Nov 2021 Lead Bartender Chicago, IL

- Assisted in the development of drinks and curation of wine, sake, and spirits.
- Fine-tuned customer service and time-management skills by leading fast paced fine dining service nightly.
- Developed and taught virtual cocktail classes using Zoom and Google Meet.
- Awards received during my tenure: Food and Wine Best New Restaurant, Time Magazine World's Greatest Places 2019, World's 50 Best Bars (82), Jean Banchet Best Bar 2020

Education

General AssemblySoftware Engineering Immersive Student

Florida State University BA Economics, Theatre

Feb 2022 – May 2022 Remote

Aug 2012 – Apr 2016 Tallahassee, FL